<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on DEV Akimbo</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on DEV Akimbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 23:29:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gh.devakimbo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Singleton Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/singleton-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 23:29:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/singleton-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this article, you will learn the most popular and the simplest design pattern that every web developer and every software developer, in general, should know about. This design pattern is Singleton.
You will not only learn how and when to use Singleton but also when not to use it.
If you are new to design patterns learning the Singleton is a good place to start.
If you are looking for a good introduction to design patterns, check out the article What is a Design Pattern.</description></item><item><title>Cookie Policy</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/cookie-policy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:59:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/cookie-policy/</guid><description>Our website uses cookies. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart.
They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services.</description></item><item><title>Terms of Service</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/terms-of-service/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 21:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/terms-of-service/</guid><description>OVERVIEW
This website is operated by Appdy LTD. Throughout the site, the terms “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Appdy.net. Appdy.net offers this website, including all information, tools and services available from this site to you, the user, conditioned upon your acceptance of all terms, conditions, policies and notices stated here.
By visiting our site and/ or purchasing something from us, you engage in our “Service” and agree to be bound by the following terms and conditions (“Terms of Service”, “Terms”), including those additional terms and conditions and policies referenced herein and/or available by hyperlink.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 19:59:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/privacy-policy/</guid><description>This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their “Personally identifiable information” (PII) is being used online. PI is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.</description></item><item><title>What Programming Language to Learn First in 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-first-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 06:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-first-in-2021/</guid><description>As you probably notice, there are plenty of programming languages, and perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s harder than ever to choose anything because there is so much noise. Everyone is recommending the programming language they know as the silver bullet, and the ideal way to start in IT.
But this is terrible advice, because if you learn something that you don&amp;rsquo;t need in the long run, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be using it daily soon, you will forget it, and your time and money investment will be wasted.</description></item><item><title>Python 3 Installation Tutorial for Beginners</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-installation-tutorial-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 21:47:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-installation-tutorial-for-beginners/</guid><description>In this article, we will set up the entire python development environment from scratch on Windows, macOS, and Linux. So if you are using any of these and you want to have python up and running you are in the right place.
This post is part of complete FREE Python Developer Crash Course that we publish on YouTube. We publish programming learning and IT Career videos advice multiple times a week so remember to subscribe to not miss any of them.</description></item><item><title>How Covid 19 Have Killed Programming Market</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-covid-19-have-killed-programming-market/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 21:38:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-covid-19-have-killed-programming-market/</guid><description>A global pandemic has hit hard every industry, and IT is no exception. This article is about what is the ugly, the bad, and good about the current situation in the IT market. As you probably noticed, I put these into reversed order, that&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;m from the West and people from the West like happy endings. So let&amp;rsquo;s leave what&amp;rsquo;s good to the very end, and let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at what&amp;rsquo;s ugly and bad about the current situation first.</description></item><item><title>Why Its Harder Than Ever to Learn Programming Today</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-its-harder-than-ever-to-learn-programming-today/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-its-harder-than-ever-to-learn-programming-today/</guid><description>In this post, we are gonna talk about why it&amp;rsquo;s harder than ever to learn programming today. I will share with you my arguments, with a couple of tips on how to deal with some of the most irritating issues.
Hey, I know this topic is controversial because the common belief is we are living in amazing times, and there is so much free and paid content. The thing is the more is not always better.</description></item><item><title>Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/chain-of-responsibility-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 22:14:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/chain-of-responsibility-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we are going to talk about the Chain of Responsibility, one of the most omnipresent design pattern in every web development framework.
This design pattern is one of these tools that every web developer should be familiar with. We don&amp;rsquo;t have to know how to code it, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to know how it works.
If you are looking for a good introduction to design patterns, check out the article What is a Design Pattern.</description></item><item><title>Lazy Initialization Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/lazy-initialization-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 14:12:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/lazy-initialization-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this post, you will learn what Lazy Initialization design pattern is, how to implement it using Python, when it makes sense to use it, and when it will be an overkill.
Lazy Initialization is one of the most popular design patterns, and every professional software developer no matter what languages he uses should be familiar with it, if he is serious about his career.
If you are looking for a good introduction to design patterns, check out the article What is a Design Pattern.</description></item><item><title>Abstract Factory Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/abstract-factory-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/abstract-factory-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this post, we will talk about the Abstract Factory design pattern, how to use it, when to use it, and what is of equal importance when not to use it. This is an advanced topic as all design patterns require an in-depth knowledge of programming language semantic, but if you are Python developer already, and you want to top up your professional skills, this video is for you.
There is a big chance you will never need to implement an Abstract Factory design pattern.</description></item><item><title>Observer Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/observer-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 18:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/observer-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this post, you will learn what Observer design pattern is, how to implement it using Python, when it makes sense to use it, and when using it will be an overkill.
If you are Angular 2 developer or you playing around with libraries like RxJS, you will find this article double helpful, because Angular2 and RxJS are heavily relying on Observer design pattern.
If you are new to design patterns read What is Design Pattern first.</description></item><item><title>Decorator Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/decorator-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 22:58:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/decorator-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>There are many tutorials and articles online about Decorator design pattern, so why I do another one? The main reason is that many people who make these tutorials don&amp;rsquo;t have much programming experience. So they provide inaccurate or misleading information.
In this tutorial, you will not only learn how Decorator pattern works in Python but also where to use it and how to use it. We will also do some coding.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Design Pattern</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-a-design-pattern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 13:05:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-a-design-pattern/</guid><description>Design patterns are the concept that is often overlooked by the beginner software developers, but what more alarming, by senior developers as well.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to demystify what design patterns are and what are the benefits of using them.
So if you are new to design patterns, you can use this post as an introduction.
What are design patterns? Design patterns are keywords used by experienced developers to communicate the solutions to the problems.</description></item><item><title>Python 3 Build in and Reserved Keywords</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-build-in-and-reserved-keywords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 18:27:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-build-in-and-reserved-keywords/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna give you the list of Python 3 reserved keywords. This list is handy when you will be creating variables, function names, and classes.
It would also help while crafting documentation and code for fellow developers to avoid making references to the concepts that are not related and could cause confusion.
Knowing these keywords will not only make you a better Python programmer but will also make you look more mature as a programmer.</description></item><item><title>How the Internet Works</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-the-internet-works/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 22:23:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-the-internet-works/</guid><description>If you are a web developer, many people will expect that you know how the web works. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t figure out that yet, this article is a good opportunity to know everything you should know without going too deep into not important details.
Client - server model Simply put, the Internet works in a client-server manner.
The client is our web browser like Chrome or Safari, and the server is an HTTP server.</description></item><item><title>What HTML5 Means</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-html5-means/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 22:43:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-html5-means/</guid><description>HTML5 is probably the most basic concept for every web developer. But because some people keep asking what does it mean, I decided to write a post to answer this question.
What is HTML? HTML is a shortcut from Hypertext Markup Language, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean anything. What matters is that it&amp;rsquo;s a language used to define a structure of the web page.
HTML is something that we, as humans can understand and use it to make web pages.</description></item><item><title>47 Git Aliases That Will Make You More Productive</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/47-git-aliases-that-will-make-you-more-productive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 21:50:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/47-git-aliases-that-will-make-you-more-productive/</guid><description>Many seasoned developers type long git commands every time they need to perform a simple task, they forget the attributes or entire commands. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame to see senior developer typing 40 characters without a second thought.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you killer git feature that sadly many developers overlook. That&amp;rsquo;s git aliases. If you know it already, bear with me because I will share with you my secret 47 aliases that I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine programming without.</description></item><item><title>Why Windows Laptops Are More Expensive Than Macbooks for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-windows-laptops-are-more-expensive-than-macbooks-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 12:44:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-windows-laptops-are-more-expensive-than-macbooks-for-web-developers/</guid><description>If you are a web developer or any kind of IT professional, buying a new laptop is probably a serious event for you.
Many people tell that the MacBook is the best choice, others say that for software development, only Linux. Others are loyal to Windows. And often, our options are limited by the amount of money in our pocket.
In this post, I will tell you how many laptops with Windows really cost for a web developer.</description></item><item><title>Best Code Editor for Web Development 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/best-code-editor-for-web-development-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 12:26:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/best-code-editor-for-web-development-2021/</guid><description>There quite a lot of code editors on the market, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get confused, especially as a beginner developer. And, as we all know, the more obstacles we have on our way, it&amp;rsquo;s less probable that we will reach our destination.
So let&amp;rsquo;s remove that obstacle and decide about only one editor that we will be used for coding purposes so we could focus on stuff that matters.</description></item><item><title>Linux Command Line for Beginners</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/linux-command-line-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 09:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/linux-command-line-for-beginners/</guid><description>Command line is one of these things that officially nobody expects you to know, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know if you will struggle hard in your entire IT career.
If you do anything with Linux and you don&amp;rsquo;t know the command line, it&amp;rsquo;s about time to change it.
In this post, you will learn the basics of the Linux command line, focusing only on the essential parts that you will be using 90% of the time.</description></item><item><title>Web App vs Website</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/web-app-vs-website/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 18:45:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/web-app-vs-website/</guid><description>There is a lot of confusion about what the website and web application are. And there is a good reason for that. They look very similar at first glance, just another we page - bunch of HTML, CSS, Javascript, and some images. The differences lie undercovers.
Let&amp;rsquo;s define what website and web application really means.
What is the website? You can think of a website as web pages that are served in the same form they were sent by the server - as a collection of HTML, CSS, Javascript files, and images.</description></item><item><title>The 5 Best Methods to Learn Programming</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-5-best-methods-to-learn-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:54:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-5-best-methods-to-learn-programming/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you the five best methods to learn programming. These rules help me learn new programming languages, frameworks, and other technologies like databases in just couple of days.
I will also give you a bonus method, that if I knew it sooner, it would save me plenty of time and money in all the opportunities I missed.
If you commit yourself to follow these rules, I promise your programming learning will skyrocket.</description></item><item><title>What Is Object Oriented Programming</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-object-oriented-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 10:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-object-oriented-programming/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna teach you what object oriented programming is. I will skip all the bollocks and explain it to you in the simplest way ever, buy using a video game as an example.
The simplest way to describe object oriented programming (also called OOP) is to use a game analogy. Why, because most of the video games are built using object oriented paradigm.
The Game Let&amp;rsquo;s use the example of the game where we have two races fighting with each other &amp;ldquo;Human and Goblins&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>What Programming Language to Learn for Web Development in 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-web-development-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 23:38:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-web-development-in-2021/</guid><description>So many people who start their way to web development ask this question, “which programming language is the best for web development”. There is a lot of confusion about this, and what web development is.
Let’s decrypt what “web development” means first.
What does “web development” actually mean? Probably the simplest definition of web development is “it’s building websites”.
So we use HTML, CSS, and maybe some Javascript and create a website, and that’s it, right?</description></item><item><title>The 6 Biggest Reasons Why You Will Fail to Learn Programming</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-6-biggest-reasons-why-you-will-fail-to-learn-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 23:24:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-6-biggest-reasons-why-you-will-fail-to-learn-programming/</guid><description>In this post, you will learn the 6 biggest reasons why you will probably fail to learn programming. But don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, there is nothing wrong with you. These are just the biggest and most common reasons why people fail to learn to code.
But as always, I will not only leave you with the list of problems. I will give you advice on how not to let them stop you.</description></item><item><title>What Programming Language to Learn for App Development in 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-app-development-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:11:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-app-development-in-2021/</guid><description>As you probably already know, there are two important platforms in mobile apps development. iOS and Android (there is also Windows, but nobody cares). To be considered that you are a mobile app developer, you have to know how to build apps for at least one of them.
When you start to advertise your skills as a mobile app developer, people will think that you know both platforms. The funny thing is, most people don&amp;rsquo;t know the difference.</description></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/contact/</guid><description>To contact us please use the contact form below. We will reply to you shortly.
Loading…</description></item></channel></rss>