<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on DEV Akimbo</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on DEV Akimbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 23:29:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gh.devakimbo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Singleton Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/singleton-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 23:29:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/singleton-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this article, you will learn the most popular and the simplest design pattern that every web developer and every software developer, in general, should know about. This design pattern is Singleton.
You will not only learn how and when to use Singleton but also when not to use it.
If you are new to design patterns learning the Singleton is a good place to start.
If you are looking for a good introduction to design patterns, check out the article What is a Design Pattern.
What is the Singleton? Singleton is a creational design pattern, that helps us make sure that our application has no more than one instance of a specific class.
That&amp;rsquo;s very handy when we want to use the same object across the application, and when we need to have an easy access to it in any place in the code.
By keeping and reusing only one instance of the class, we reduce the application load time, memory consumption, code readability, and maintainability.
Thanks to this pattern, we also don&amp;rsquo;t have to think about how we can access the instance. The solution to this problem is already build-in the design pattern.
Creating Singleton in Python Let&amp;rsquo;s implement Singleton for Logger object.</description></item><item><title>Cookie Policy</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/cookie-policy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 15:59:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/cookie-policy/</guid><description>Our website uses cookies. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart.
They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.
We use cookies to Help remember and process the items in the shopping cart. Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits. Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf. For remarketing services through 3rd party services. Cookies we use Depending on the purpose, cookies we use are categorised in one of the following categories: necessary, marketing, analytics.</description></item><item><title>Terms of Service</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/terms-of-service/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 21:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/terms-of-service/</guid><description>OVERVIEW
This website is operated by Appdy LTD. Throughout the site, the terms “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Appdy.net. Appdy.net offers this website, including all information, tools and services available from this site to you, the user, conditioned upon your acceptance of all terms, conditions, policies and notices stated here.
By visiting our site and/ or purchasing something from us, you engage in our “Service” and agree to be bound by the following terms and conditions (“Terms of Service”, “Terms”), including those additional terms and conditions and policies referenced herein and/or available by hyperlink. These Terms of Service apply to all users of the site, including without limitation users who are browsers, vendors, customers, merchants, and/ or contributors of content.
Please read these Terms of Service carefully before accessing or using our website. By accessing or using any part of the site, you agree to be bound by these Terms of Service. If you do not agree to all the terms and conditions of this agreement, then you may not access the website or use any services. If these Terms of Service are considered an offer, acceptance is expressly limited to these Terms of Service.
Any new features or tools which are added to the current store shall also be subject to the Terms of Service.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 19:59:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/privacy-policy/</guid><description>This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their “Personally identifiable information” (PII) is being used online. PI is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.
What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app? When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, credit card information or other details so that we can provide our services to you.
When do we collect information? We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form or enter information on our site.
How do we use your information? We may use such information in the following ways:
To personalize your experience on our site and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.</description></item><item><title>What Programming Language to Learn First in 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-first-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 06:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-first-in-2021/</guid><description>As you probably notice, there are plenty of programming languages, and perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s harder than ever to choose anything because there is so much noise. Everyone is recommending the programming language they know as the silver bullet, and the ideal way to start in IT.
But this is terrible advice, because if you learn something that you don&amp;rsquo;t need in the long run, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be using it daily soon, you will forget it, and your time and money investment will be wasted. Nobody wants that.
So what programming language to learn first?
How we used to learn programming Let me tell you how it used to work in the past.
If you would start learning programming between 2000-2010 (and earlier), people will tell you, learn Pascal first because it&amp;rsquo;s the easiest programming language to learn, later it would be much easier to learn anything.
There were plenty of books with code examples, written in Pascal.
The problem with Pascal was you can&amp;rsquo;t build anything serious, with it, anything that has a market value. The only value in this language was that the semantic was very simple, so it was a helpful tool to understand basic programming concepts and algorithms.</description></item><item><title>Python 3 Installation Tutorial for Beginners</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-installation-tutorial-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 21:47:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-installation-tutorial-for-beginners/</guid><description>In this article, we will set up the entire python development environment from scratch on Windows, macOS, and Linux. So if you are using any of these and you want to have python up and running you are in the right place.
This post is part of complete FREE Python Developer Crash Course that we publish on YouTube. We publish programming learning and IT Career videos advice multiple times a week so remember to subscribe to not miss any of them.
To checkout entire course click the link.
Table of Contents Python setup on Windows Installing Visual Studio Code on Windows Python setup on macOS Installing Python on macOS via python.org Installing Python on macOS via Homebrew Installing Python on macOS via pyenv - the best option Visual Studio Code Installation on macOS Python setup on Linux Installing Python on Linux via a package manager Installing Python on Linux via pyenv Visual Studio Code Installation on Linux Visual Studio Code Final Setup Conclusion After installing python we will install and configure Visual Studio Code. You may ask&amp;hellip;
Why Visual Studio Code?
Visual Studio Code is the easiest to use and most feature-rich code editor available and it&amp;rsquo;s free.</description></item><item><title>How Covid 19 Have Killed Programming Market</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-covid-19-have-killed-programming-market/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 21:38:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-covid-19-have-killed-programming-market/</guid><description>A global pandemic has hit hard every industry, and IT is no exception. This article is about what is the ugly, the bad, and good about the current situation in the IT market. As you probably noticed, I put these into reversed order, that&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;m from the West and people from the West like happy endings. So let&amp;rsquo;s leave what&amp;rsquo;s good to the very end, and let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at what&amp;rsquo;s ugly and bad about the current situation first.
The Ugly People are losing their jobs You may hear of some markets are doing well like video conferencing, telemedicine, e-commerce, delivery, food groceries, streaming games, SaaS, security, telecoms, and online advertising, while other declines.
Sadly, for us IT individuals, many of us lost their jobs, many projects were delayed or canceled. It happened before most of the countries adapted to the situation and put employee retention schemas at a place to protect workers from being laid off. Sadly it didn&amp;rsquo;t work in every case.
The contractors were out of luck the most. As they are not protected by the employer-employee regulations, many contracts were suddenly canceled.
Fake job positions Even if we can find job opportunities on job boards, many of them are just baits and these opportunities don&amp;rsquo;t exist at all.</description></item><item><title>Why Its Harder Than Ever to Learn Programming Today</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-its-harder-than-ever-to-learn-programming-today/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-its-harder-than-ever-to-learn-programming-today/</guid><description>In this post, we are gonna talk about why it&amp;rsquo;s harder than ever to learn programming today. I will share with you my arguments, with a couple of tips on how to deal with some of the most irritating issues.
Hey, I know this topic is controversial because the common belief is we are living in amazing times, and there is so much free and paid content. The thing is the more is not always better.
Too many technologies If you want to become a software developer, not only a web developer, but a professional programmer, in general, you will face more options to choose from than we ever had.
When I first started learning programming, there were only a couple of serious technologies that would give me any chance to get a job. Back then, I know that some of the technologies we&amp;rsquo;re already falling behind, and they are kept alive only to support legacy applications.
The ones that would give me access to new projects and were trending were Java (with plenty of related frameworks), PHP, or C#, above that, I had need to know one of popular databases Oracle, MySQL or Postgresql and a bit of Linux command line, and I was all set.</description></item><item><title>Chain of Responsibility Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/chain-of-responsibility-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 22:14:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/chain-of-responsibility-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we are going to talk about the Chain of Responsibility, one of the most omnipresent design pattern in every web development framework.
This design pattern is one of these tools that every web developer should be familiar with. We don&amp;rsquo;t have to know how to code it, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to know how it works.
If you are looking for a good introduction to design patterns, check out the article What is a Design Pattern.
What is the Chain of Responsibility design pattern? It&amp;rsquo;s probably safe to say that unless you want to create your own routing library or request processing framework, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t need to implement this pattern ever. Nevertheless, if you are a web developer, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to know how it works, because it&amp;rsquo;s used in probably every implementation of server-side HTTP request processing frameworks and routing libraries.
The Chain of responsibility is a behavioral design pattern where incoming tasks are handled by handlers lined up in the order. Every handler who receives a task may process it, pass it over, or break the chain and stop the task from propagating to the next handler.
Multiple handlers may handle the incoming task without mutual knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Lazy Initialization Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/lazy-initialization-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 14:12:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/lazy-initialization-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this post, you will learn what Lazy Initialization design pattern is, how to implement it using Python, when it makes sense to use it, and when it will be an overkill.
Lazy Initialization is one of the most popular design patterns, and every professional software developer no matter what languages he uses should be familiar with it, if he is serious about his career.
If you are looking for a good introduction to design patterns, check out the article What is a Design Pattern.
What is the Lazy Initialization design pattern? The Lazy Initialization, also called Lazy Loading is a very simple but powerful a creational design pattern that allows us to delay initialization of the object until it is needed.
It is used to increase application performance, speed up the initialization process, and reduces resource consumption: bandwidth, database load, RAM, and CPU usage.
Using Lazy Initialization in Python Let&amp;rsquo;s assume we have implemented an online shop where we have an object Customer that may have a list of orders he created. Without Lazy Loading, we would probably have an entire list of orders retrieved from the database every time we will create object Customer. Even if there were no orders in the customer account, we would query the database.</description></item><item><title>Abstract Factory Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/abstract-factory-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/abstract-factory-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this post, we will talk about the Abstract Factory design pattern, how to use it, when to use it, and what is of equal importance when not to use it. This is an advanced topic as all design patterns require an in-depth knowledge of programming language semantic, but if you are Python developer already, and you want to top up your professional skills, this video is for you.
There is a big chance you will never need to implement an Abstract Factory design pattern. Still, it definitely pays off to know it, not only because it&amp;rsquo;s a shame to be a professional developer who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know it - it is a shame, though - but also it will improve your object-oriented programming sense.
And the beauty of every design pattern is you can use it across the languages.
If you are looking for a good introduction to design patterns, check out the article What is a Design Pattern.
What is the Abstract Factory Design Pattern? Abstract Factory is a creational design pattern used when we want to have a way to create objects of a specific type when the type of created objects can be easily switched without changing the code.</description></item><item><title>Observer Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/observer-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 18:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/observer-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>In this post, you will learn what Observer design pattern is, how to implement it using Python, when it makes sense to use it, and when using it will be an overkill.
If you are Angular 2 developer or you playing around with libraries like RxJS, you will find this article double helpful, because Angular2 and RxJS are heavily relying on Observer design pattern.
If you are new to design patterns read What is Design Pattern first.
What is the Observer design pattern? The Observer is a behavioral design pattern. The easiest way to think of it is as a publisher-subscribers kind of relationship between objects. Some of the objects may want to get notified when another object state will change and handle it in some way.
Creating Observer in Python There are many many ways to implement the Observer design pattern. I propose what used to works best for myself, the implementation that is inspired by the RxJS library.
from abc import ABC class Observer(ABC): def handle_event(self, state): pass class Observable(ABC): def __init__(self, state): self._observers = set() self.state = state def subscribe(self, observer): self._observers.add(observer) def unsubscribe(self, observer): self._observers.discard(observer) def changeState(self, state): if (self.state != state): self.state = state for observer in self.</description></item><item><title>Decorator Design Pattern Python for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/decorator-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 22:58:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/decorator-design-pattern-python-for-web-developers/</guid><description>There are many tutorials and articles online about Decorator design pattern, so why I do another one? The main reason is that many people who make these tutorials don&amp;rsquo;t have much programming experience. So they provide inaccurate or misleading information.
In this tutorial, you will not only learn how Decorator pattern works in Python but also where to use it and how to use it. We will also do some coding.
If you are new to design patterns read What is Design Pattern first.
What is the Decorator? In a nutshell, Python decorator is a function that wraps another function and controls its execution. We do that to enhance the functionality of the wrapped function, without changing implementation of that function.
Decorator is a structural design pattern, because it simplify the design of relationships between entities.
Creating Decorator in Python Let&amp;rsquo;s first create a function that we want to decorate.
def house(): print(&amp;#34;house&amp;#34;) And the decorator function itself:
def with_garden(f): def with_garden_nested(): f() print(&amp;#34;with garden&amp;#34;) return with_garden_nested The with_garden function takes a function as a parameter. The with_garden_nested is a nested function inside of with_garden. We then use the Python feature called &amp;ldquo;closure&amp;rdquo; to refer to the outer function parameter f and call it.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Design Pattern</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-a-design-pattern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 13:05:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-a-design-pattern/</guid><description>Design patterns are the concept that is often overlooked by the beginner software developers, but what more alarming, by senior developers as well.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to demystify what design patterns are and what are the benefits of using them.
So if you are new to design patterns, you can use this post as an introduction.
What are design patterns? Design patterns are keywords used by experienced developers to communicate the solutions to the problems.
They are like templates, ways of structuring the code in a way that is proven to solve a particular group of problems successfully.
They are like small and big elements that every application uses behind the scene.
Benefits of design patterns Here are the most significant benefits of using design patterns.
Design patterns as communication language of PROs Experienced developers know design patterns…
At least some of them…
At least they should.
When you speak with your colegues, you can make an analogy to specific design patterns to better describe your point. That way, it&amp;rsquo;s far easier for your colleagues to imagine the solution you have on your mind.
Design patterns as solutions to common problems Design patterns are abstractions that describe a common solution to a particular group of problems.</description></item><item><title>Python 3 Build in and Reserved Keywords</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-build-in-and-reserved-keywords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 18:27:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/python-3-build-in-and-reserved-keywords/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna give you the list of Python 3 reserved keywords. This list is handy when you will be creating variables, function names, and classes.
It would also help while crafting documentation and code for fellow developers to avoid making references to the concepts that are not related and could cause confusion.
Knowing these keywords will not only make you a better Python programmer but will also make you look more mature as a programmer.
Newbie coders often forgot that the particular word is a reserved keyword, and create confusing names for functions and variables. They don&amp;rsquo;t know or remember all the abstractions enclosed in the programming language. And it&amp;rsquo;s common for inexperienced developers. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be perceived as one of them, do you?
The list is not hard to remember, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to learn it. Instead, read it once or twice, and go back to it every time you need to refresh your memory while working with the code.
Over time you will notice that you will know every element on the list without learning it.
The list is grouped by the context where a particular keyword can occur.
Boolean related True False Special values None Module asyncio related async await Modules related import - used to import the content of the module into the current module as - used together with &amp;lsquo;import&amp;rsquo; specifies an alias for imported module from - used together with &amp;lsquo;import&amp;rsquo;, it specifies the module to import, and &amp;lsquo;import&amp;rsquo; specifies what functions will be imported Functions related def - define function pass - skip the function definition return - return value from the function lambda - used for creating anonymous, inline functions, without self parameter global - used for declaring a variable inside a function as global (as it was declared outside the function) nonlocal - marks the variable that it refers to the variable defined outside the function, used only when we change the value in nested function (closures) Conditional statements related if - starts a conditional block else - alternative block in a conditional block elif - alternative conditional block with condition check is - returns true if two objects are the same Logical operators and - expression result into True only if both operands are True or - expression result into True only if any of operands is True not - expression result into True only if the operand is False in - used to test if a sequence (string, list, tuple) contains a value Loops related for - starts for loop block while - starts while loop block break - exit execution of the loop continue - skips current loop iteration and go to the next one Control flow with - declares a control-flow structure as - used together with &amp;lsquo;with&amp;rsquo; Exceptions related try - starts try/except block raise - throws an exception except - starts specific exception handling block finally - starts block executed after the try/except block execution is finished Class related class - used to declare a class pass - used to declare that child class will have the same declaration as it&amp;rsquo;s parent class del - deletes the class Variables related del - deletes the variable or removes value from the sequence (list, tuple, string) Generators related yield - pauses generator execution and returns the value Assertion related assert - declares assertion condition Conclusion The list of Python keywords is a good asset to have on hand.</description></item><item><title>How the Internet Works</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-the-internet-works/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 22:23:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/how-the-internet-works/</guid><description>If you are a web developer, many people will expect that you know how the web works. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t figure out that yet, this article is a good opportunity to know everything you should know without going too deep into not important details.
Client - server model Simply put, the Internet works in a client-server manner.
The client is our web browser like Chrome or Safari, and the server is an HTTP server. HTTP is the protocol used for communication between them.
The Internet is built with a global, vast network of data centers connected together via optical fiber wires.
Data centers host HTTP servers, databases, and other things.
fig 1. Network of data centers Client request a website When we want to visit any particular website, we type the domain name, and the browser, in a magical way, takes us to the requested web page.
Not really magical, but what happens undercovers the browser don&amp;rsquo;t know what does amazon.com means, so he has to ask nearest DNS server, domain name resolution server - and there are networks of them as well - for IP address of the amazon.com. Because the browser needs an IP address, he is not happy with just having a domain name.</description></item><item><title>What HTML5 Means</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-html5-means/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 22:43:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-html5-means/</guid><description>HTML5 is probably the most basic concept for every web developer. But because some people keep asking what does it mean, I decided to write a post to answer this question.
What is HTML? HTML is a shortcut from Hypertext Markup Language, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean anything. What matters is that it&amp;rsquo;s a language used to define a structure of the web page.
HTML is something that we, as humans can understand and use it to make web pages. Internet browsers understand this notation as well. So thanks to HTML, humans and the machines may speak the same language.
HTML is used only for defining the structure of the web page, meta information and additional assets like inline scripts or stylesheets, or references to external ones.
We don&amp;rsquo;t use HTML to define what color or layout the web page will have. For this purpose, we use CSS, which stands for Cascading Style Sheets.
HTML web page is just a simple text document written in HTML syntax.
What is HTML5? The HTML5 is a modern version of HTML, and it&amp;rsquo;s known as an HTML Living Standard, which means it&amp;rsquo;s keeps updated with new elements and features.
Why we need HTML5?</description></item><item><title>47 Git Aliases That Will Make You More Productive</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/47-git-aliases-that-will-make-you-more-productive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 21:50:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/47-git-aliases-that-will-make-you-more-productive/</guid><description>Many seasoned developers type long git commands every time they need to perform a simple task, they forget the attributes or entire commands. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame to see senior developer typing 40 characters without a second thought.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you killer git feature that sadly many developers overlook. That&amp;rsquo;s git aliases. If you know it already, bear with me because I will share with you my secret 47 aliases that I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine programming without.
If you use git a lot via command line and you probably already know what git aliases are.
If you use any GUI tool instead of the terminal to run git commands, well, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that after you get familiar with git aliases, you will switch your git workflow entirely to the terminal.
Git aliases are a simple but very effective way to increase our productivity while using git.
If you are new to git aliases, let me give you a brief introduction.
For example, if you want to display the repository log as a nice colored tree, you will type something like this.
git log --graph --date=relative --pretty=tformat:&amp;#39;%Cred%h%Creset -%C(auto)%d%Creset %s %Cgreen(%an %ad)%Creset&amp;#39; If you have an alias, you can just type git ls to get the same effect.</description></item><item><title>Why Windows Laptops Are More Expensive Than Macbooks for Web Developers</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-windows-laptops-are-more-expensive-than-macbooks-for-web-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 12:44:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/why-windows-laptops-are-more-expensive-than-macbooks-for-web-developers/</guid><description>If you are a web developer or any kind of IT professional, buying a new laptop is probably a serious event for you.
Many people tell that the MacBook is the best choice, others say that for software development, only Linux. Others are loyal to Windows. And often, our options are limited by the amount of money in our pocket.
In this post, I will tell you how many laptops with Windows really cost for a web developer. What is the official practice, and what are the hidden.
In this post, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to contribute to holy war, which operating system and which laptop is better for software development - web development in particular. Instead, I will share with you my honest opinion build during 15 years of my career as a web developer.
How much laptop with Windows really cost? Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that you, as a web developer, decided to buy a new laptop with Windows.
Let&amp;rsquo;s also assume it&amp;rsquo;s a 2020 HP 15.6&amp;quot; Touchscreen Laptop Computer/ 10th Gen Intel Quard-Core i7 1065G7 up to 3.9GHz/ 16GB DDR4 RAM/ 1TB PCIe SSD/ 802.11ac WiFi/ Silver/ Windows 10+ EST 500GB External Hard Drive Bundle gosh.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember when last time I saw these kinds of crazy titles.</description></item><item><title>Best Code Editor for Web Development 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/best-code-editor-for-web-development-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 12:26:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/best-code-editor-for-web-development-2021/</guid><description>There quite a lot of code editors on the market, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get confused, especially as a beginner developer. And, as we all know, the more obstacles we have on our way, it&amp;rsquo;s less probable that we will reach our destination.
So let&amp;rsquo;s remove that obstacle and decide about only one editor that we will be used for coding purposes so we could focus on stuff that matters.
For your convenience, I created a list of top free code editors below.
Why only free?
Because as of 2021, free editors provide all the features web developer could ever dream of just a few years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to buy anything more.
Visual Studio Code (VSC) Visual Studio Code screenshot On the very top of the list landed a real dark horse of recent years. Thanks to big changes in Microsoft attitude from &amp;ldquo;open source is a cancer&amp;rdquo;, to &amp;ldquo;open source is a future&amp;rdquo;, Visual Studio Code joined to the collection of great open source tools that many of us couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine to code without it.
Visual Studio Code has all the basic features any coder would expect from the code editor.</description></item><item><title>Linux Command Line for Beginners</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/linux-command-line-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 09:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/linux-command-line-for-beginners/</guid><description>Command line is one of these things that officially nobody expects you to know, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know if you will struggle hard in your entire IT career.
If you do anything with Linux and you don&amp;rsquo;t know the command line, it&amp;rsquo;s about time to change it.
In this post, you will learn the basics of the Linux command line, focusing only on the essential parts that you will be using 90% of the time.
By the way, all the information in this post relates to the terminal in Linux and macOS. I don&amp;rsquo;t cover the Windows command line here, which used to be significantly different.
Command Line, Terminal, Console First, let&amp;rsquo;s clear the meaning of this word because, as you probably have noticed, some people say command line, terminal, or console interchangeably.
A terminal runs in a graphical environment on its own window.
The console mode is available when we didn&amp;rsquo;t start a graphical environment, or we boot our computer is one of recovery or emergency modes.
In practice, there is no much of the difference if we run the command line in the console or terminal. This is probably the biggest reason why people use phrases command line, terminal, and console as aliases.</description></item><item><title>Web App vs Website</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/web-app-vs-website/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 18:45:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/web-app-vs-website/</guid><description>There is a lot of confusion about what the website and web application are. And there is a good reason for that. They look very similar at first glance, just another we page - bunch of HTML, CSS, Javascript, and some images. The differences lie undercovers.
Let&amp;rsquo;s define what website and web application really means.
What is the website? You can think of a website as web pages that are served in the same form they were sent by the server - as a collection of HTML, CSS, Javascript files, and images.
Every time a user switches between pages, another request to the server is made, and the new view is returned every time as HTML, CSS, Javascript images, and so on.
A typical website can by a static HTML document served from the server (with all the complementary resources) or dynamic HTML rendered by the server, for example, by Wordpress.
Most of the time, websites don&amp;rsquo;t use fancy modern Javascript frameworks like React, Angular, or Vue, because they don&amp;rsquo;t have to. An entire HTML document is already rendered on the server, styles are provided, and user interactions are served by good old jQuery or even plain Javascript.
Alternative ways to build a websites In practice, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to build a website if you need one, you can avoid buying the hosting, setting up the server and all of this web admin burden by using one of the services like Wix, Squarespace, or Webflow.</description></item><item><title>The 5 Best Methods to Learn Programming</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-5-best-methods-to-learn-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:54:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-5-best-methods-to-learn-programming/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you the five best methods to learn programming. These rules help me learn new programming languages, frameworks, and other technologies like databases in just couple of days.
I will also give you a bonus method, that if I knew it sooner, it would save me plenty of time and money in all the opportunities I missed.
If you commit yourself to follow these rules, I promise your programming learning will skyrocket.
If some of them sound too simple to be true, then give them a try every day, for a week, and check how much progress you have made. How much more confident you feel about the technology you are learning.
You will notice that all of these rules are connected, and they play together very well.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the first one, which is&amp;hellip;
Code a lot First and foremost, you have to code a lot.
You don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait until you read all of the coding books or watch all the gurus on Youtube to write code. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait until you are a good programmer before you start coding. If you wait for it to happen, let me tell you, it will never happen.</description></item><item><title>What Is Object Oriented Programming</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-object-oriented-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 10:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-is-object-oriented-programming/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna teach you what object oriented programming is. I will skip all the bollocks and explain it to you in the simplest way ever, buy using a video game as an example.
The simplest way to describe object oriented programming (also called OOP) is to use a game analogy. Why, because most of the video games are built using object oriented paradigm.
The Game Let&amp;rsquo;s use the example of the game where we have two races fighting with each other &amp;ldquo;Human and Goblins&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a 3rd person perspective role-playing game, and you can take a side of goblins or humans.
If you choose humans, you will lead a group of human heroes protecting peasants from bands of goblins. If you choose goblins, you will lead a group of goblin heroes protecting peasants from bands of humans.
We will use UML2 class diagram notation for modeling.
Classes and objects To model this world, we will have object Human. It can look like this. Human has properties typical to the characteristics that all of us has. He has a first name, last name, date of birth, gender, and national insurance number. UML2 class diagram for Human type</description></item><item><title>What Programming Language to Learn for Web Development in 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-web-development-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 23:38:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-web-development-in-2021/</guid><description>So many people who start their way to web development ask this question, “which programming language is the best for web development”. There is a lot of confusion about this, and what web development is.
Let’s decrypt what “web development” means first.
What does “web development” actually mean? Probably the simplest definition of web development is “it’s building websites”.
So we use HTML, CSS, and maybe some Javascript and create a website, and that’s it, right?
Well, there is actually a bit more to it. There are web servers that generate HTML for us. There are CSS preprocessors. There are Javascript frameworks like Angular, React, and Vue. There is jQuery, PHP, Python, and everything else.
Yes, it’s all included in web development, and definition on Wikipedia confirms that.
So if you are after becoming a web developer, you have to find your way through all these technologies, choose something that makes sense, market value, and become master of your craft.
Is web development means “a lot of money”? I assume that at least half of your motivation to become a software developer is about money, and you heard that programmers earn up to $200k or so.
Well, let’s look at some job board services like indeed.</description></item><item><title>The 6 Biggest Reasons Why You Will Fail to Learn Programming</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-6-biggest-reasons-why-you-will-fail-to-learn-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 23:24:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/the-6-biggest-reasons-why-you-will-fail-to-learn-programming/</guid><description>In this post, you will learn the 6 biggest reasons why you will probably fail to learn programming. But don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, there is nothing wrong with you. These are just the biggest and most common reasons why people fail to learn to code.
But as always, I will not only leave you with the list of problems. I will give you advice on how not to let them stop you.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Reason 6 - focus on too advanced topics When we are just starting, it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to jump into one of the fancy technology that many people are evangelizing over the internet. The problem is, it&amp;rsquo;s probably too advanced for the beginner. And you should build a strong foundation first before starting with these advanced topics.
I know it easier said than done. We are living in the age of information, and there is no much noise around. If you type any programming language name on Google, you will get results that direct you on the land mine for beginners, the same with gurus on Youtube.
These people will gladly put you on the land mine because they earn money while doing that. Furthermore, often the course they are selling how to code in X, is the only thing they know, so they can&amp;rsquo;t tell you which language is the best because they know only one.</description></item><item><title>What Programming Language to Learn for App Development in 2021</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-app-development-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:11:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/posts/what-programming-language-to-learn-for-app-development-in-2021/</guid><description>As you probably already know, there are two important platforms in mobile apps development. iOS and Android (there is also Windows, but nobody cares). To be considered that you are a mobile app developer, you have to know how to build apps for at least one of them.
When you start to advertise your skills as a mobile app developer, people will think that you know both platforms. The funny thing is, most people don&amp;rsquo;t know the difference.
Ok, but iOS and Android are totally different platforms, with different codebases, and build upon different architecture principles. How to start learning to code for mobile and not get overwhelmed by that?
Choose the platform If you just starting with mobile app development, I would choose the platform first iOS or Android and then select tech stack.
The choice depends on many factors, from personal preferences, hardware availability (iOS development requires OS X), and available market opportunities.
Choosing a single platform at the beginning is critically important for mobile development because iOS and Android systems work in a totally different way, and they utilize a different set of tools and programming languages.
Pure iOS developer scenario Let&amp;rsquo;s assume I have a Macbook, and I want to learn how to build mobile apps for iOS.</description></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>https://gh.devakimbo.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gh.devakimbo.com/contact/</guid><description>To contact us please use the contact form below. We will reply to you shortly.
Loading…</description></item></channel></rss>